<Name>à blanc</Name>
<Desc>A French term meaning "in white" and identifying foods, usually meats, that aren't browned during cooking.</Desc>
<Name>à la</Name>
<Desc>A French idiom meaning "in the manner (or style) of"; the full phrase is à la mode de. In cooking, this phrase designates the style of preparation or a particular garnish.  <em>A la bourguignonne</em>, for example, would mean "as prepared in Burgundy."</Desc>
<Name>à la carte</Name>
<Desc>A menu term signifying that each item is priced separately. See also prix fixe; table d'hôte.</Desc>
<Name>à la diable</Name>
<Desc><em>see </em>diable sauce</Desc>
<Name>à la king</Name>
<Desc>A dish of diced food (usually chicken or turkey) in a rich cream sauce containing mushrooms, pimientos, green peppers and sometimes sherry.</Desc>
<Name>à la mode</Name>
<Desc>French for "in the manner (or mode)[of]," referring to the style in which a dish is prepared. The term has been Americanized to also mean pie topped with ice cream.</Desc>
<Name>a labarigoule</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>à point</Name>
<Desc>1. The French term used for food cooked just to the perfect point of doneness. 2. When referring to meat, à point means that a steak is cooked rare.</Desc>
<Name>abalone</Name>
<Desc>A gastropod mollusk (see both listings) found along the coastlines of California, Mexico and Japan. The edible portion is the adductor muscle, a broad foot by which the abalone clings to rocks. As with any muscle, the meat is tough and must be pounded to tenderize it before cooking. Abalone, used widely in Chinese and Japanese cooking, can be purchased fresh, canned, dried or salted. Fresh abalone should smell sweet, not fishy. It should also be alivethe exposed muscle should move when touched. Choose those that are relatively small and refrigerate as soon as possible. Cook abalone within a day of purchase. Fresh abalone is best sautéed and should be cooked very briefly (20 to 30 seconds per side) or the meat will quickly toughen. Abalone is known as ormer in the English Channel, awabi in Japan, muttonfish in Australia and paua in New Zealand. Its iridescent shell is a source of mother-of-pearl. See also shellfish.</Desc>
<Name>abbacchio</Name>
<Desc>Italian for a very young lamb.</Desc>
<Name>Abbaye de Belloc (Bellocq)</Name>
<Desc>Semihard sheep's-milk cheese that's been made for centuries by the Benedictine monks at the Abbey de Belloc in the Pays Basque area of southwestern France. The cheese is traditionally made with milk from Manech sheep, though milk from other breeds may be used. It comes in 8- to 11-pound wheels with a hard brownish rind and a pale ivory interior. Abbaye de Belloc has a rich buttery flavor with hints of nuts, fruit and caramel. <em>See also </em>cheese.</Desc>
<Name>abby</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>aboyeur</Name>
<Desc><em>see</em> brigade system</Desc>
<Name>abruzzese</Name>
<Desc>An Italian descriptor for dishes (from pasta to veal) characterized by the liberal use of hot chiles, in the style of Italy's Abruzzo region.</Desc>
<Name>absinthe</Name>
<Desc>Reputed to be an aphrodisiac, absinthe is a potent, bitter liqueur distilled from wormwood and flavored with a variety of herbs. It has a distinct anise flavor and is 68 percent alcohol (136 proof). Absinthe is usually diluted with water, which changes the color of the liqueur from green to milky white. Because it's considered habit forming and hazardous to health, absinthe is prohibited in many countries and was banned in the United States in the early 1900s.</Desc>
<Name>açai</Name>
<Desc>Native to the tropical areas of Central and South America, the açai berry is being touted as the new superfood and is known by some as the "power berry." That's because it's exceedingly rich in nutrients including antioxidants, vitamins, minerals, oleic acid and potassium, to name a few. The dark purple grape-sized fruit grows on the açai palm, which is also called the cabbage palm because natives eat its young, tender leaf buds as one would cabbage. Hearts of palm is another food source harvested from this tall palm. The açai berry contains only a small portion of pulpabout 90 percent of it is an inedible nut. The pulp, which has a flavor reminiscent of berries with a hint of chocolate, is quite delicate and deteriorates quickly. That's why consumers in North America only have access to açai in juice form (primarily as a concentrate), which can be found in the refrigerated or freezer section of natural food stores. It's also available as frozen pulp, or in a powdered form. Because of its ascribed health benefits, açai has become a favorite addition to smoothies.</Desc>
<Name>acai berry</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>Ac'cent</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>acerola</Name>
<Desc>A tiny tree and the small, deep-red, cherrylike fruit that grows on it, found primarily in and around the West Indies. The fruit, which has a sweet flavor and one of the highest concentrations of vitamin C, is used in desserts and preserves. It's also called  Barbados cherry, Puerto Rican cherry and West Indies cherry.</Desc>
<Name>Acesulfame-K</Name>
<Desc>Formulated by the Germans in the late 1960s, this noncaloric artificial sweetener (also called Ace-K and acesulfame potassium) was approved in the United States by the Federal Drug Administration in 1988. It's 200 times sweeter than sugar and, unlike aspartame, retains its sweetness when heated, making it suitable for cooking and baking. When used in large amounts, however, Ace-K has a bitter aftertaste, much like that of saccharin. This sweetener is composed of carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, hydrogen, sulphur and potassium atoms. It's widely used in a broad range of commercial products including baked goods, candies and imitation dairy products. See also alitame; neotame; sucralose.</Desc>
<Name>acetic acid</Name>
<Desc>Acetic acid is formed when common airborne bacteria interact with the alcohol present in fermented solutions such as wine, beer or cider. Acetic acid is the constituent that makes vinegar sour.</Desc>
<Name>aceto</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "vinegar."</Desc>
<Name>achar</Name>
<Desc>An East Indian word referring to pickled and salted relishes. They can be sweet or hot, depending on the seasoning added.</Desc>
<Name>achiote seed</Name>
<Desc>The slightly musky-flavored seed of the annatto tree is available whole or ground in East Indian, Spanish and Latin American markets. Buy whole seeds when they're a rusty red color; brown seeds are old and flavorless. Achiote seed is also called annatto which, in its paste and powder form, is used in the United States to color butter, margarine, cheese and smoked fish.</Desc>
<Name>acid</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>acid orange</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>acidophilous milk</Name>
<Desc>see milk</Desc>
<Name>acidulated water</Name>
<Desc>Water to which a small amount of vinegar, lemon or lime juice has been added. It's used as a soak to prevent discoloration of some fruits and vegetables (such as apples and artichokes) that darken quickly when their cut surfaces are exposed to air. It can also be used as a cooking medium.</Desc>
<Name>acini di pepe</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "peppercorns." Tiny rice-shaped pasta.</Desc>
<Name>acitrón acitrónes</Name>
<Desc>pl. see nopales</Desc>
<Name>ackee</Name>
<Desc>A bright red tropical fruit that, when ripe, bursts open to reveal three large black seeds and a soft, creamy white flesh. The scientific name, blighia sapida, comes from Captain Bligh, who brought the fruit from West Africa to Jamaica in 1793. It is extremely popular in one of Jamaica's national dishes, "saltfish and ackee." Because certain parts of the fruit are toxic when underripe, canned ackee is often subject to import restrictions.</Desc>
<Name>acorn</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>acorn squash</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>acqua</Name>
<Desc>Italian for water.</Desc>
<Name>additives, food</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>ade</Name>
<Desc>A drink, such as <b>lemonade</b> or <b>limeade,</b> made by combining water, sugar and citrus juice.</Desc>
<Name>adjust, to</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>adobado</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>adobo</Name>
<Desc>1. In Mexico, adobo is a dark-red, fairly piquant sauce (or paste) made from ground chiles, herbs and vinegar. It's used as a marinade as well as for a cooking and serving sauce. Chipotle chiles are often marketed packed in adobo sauce. Adobo also describes a stewlike presentation of meat prepared in this sauce. The word <em>adobado </em>is used as an adjective for dishes that are prepared in this manner. 2. In the Philippines, adobo is a dish of meat (typically chicken, pork or beef) and occasionally fish that's been marinated in a mixture of palm vinegar, garlic, herbs, spices and sometimes coconut milk. The meat is browned before being simmered in a blend of the marinade and soy sauce. Coconut milk is sometimes added to the Filipino adobo, which is considered by many to be the country's national dish.</Desc>
<Name>adobo sauce</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>advocaat</Name>
<Desc>A Dutch, brandy-based eggnog-flavored liqueur. The full name is advocaatenborrel, Dutch for "advocate's (or lawyer's) drink."</Desc>
<Name>aemono</Name>
<Desc>Japanese term meaning "dressed foods" and referring to saladlike dishes combined with a dressing complimentary to the ingredients. The composition of the dressings varies but is generally based on puréed tofu. Aemono dishes are usually served chilled as appetizers, although Japanese diners sometimes eat them towards the end of a meal prior to the rice.</Desc>
<Name>aerate</Name>
<Desc>A term used in cookery as a synonym for sift.</Desc>
<Name>Affidelice</Name>
<Desc><em>see </em>époisses</Desc>
<Name>affinage</Name>
<Desc>The French term for the process of finishing (ripening) cheese to bring it to a perfect point of maturity. <em>See also </em>affiné.</Desc>
<Name>affinatore</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>affiné</Name>
<Desc><em>Fr. affineur</em> <em>It. affinatore</em> In the cheese world the term <em>affiné </em>most often refers to the process of ripening cheesebringing it to peak maturity. In France an <em>affineur</em> is an expert in finishing (aging) cheese; in Italy this specialist is called an <em>affinatore</em>. Some cheesemakers turn their unripe cheese over to an <em>affineur, </em>who brings it to maturity. An <em>affineur's</em> duties may also include everything from packaging to marketing the cheese. Both words are from the French <em>affiner </em>("to finish"). <em>See also affinage</em></Desc>
<Name>affineur</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>affogato</Name>
<Desc>A scoop of vanilla gelato or ice cream topped with a shot of hot espresso. Though vanilla is traditional, chocolate gelato is sometimes used, in which case the dessert becomes <em>affogato mocha.</em> The word <em>affogato</em> comes from the Italian <em>affogare </em>("drown").</Desc>
<Name>affumicata</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "smoked," as in smoked meat or smoked cheese.</Desc>
<Name>affumicato</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>African horned cucumber</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>agar</Name>
<Desc>Also called kanten and Japanese gelatin, this tasteless dried seaweed acts as a setting agent and is widely used in Asia. It is marketed in the form of blocks, powder or brittle strands and is available at Asian markets and natural food stores. Agar can be substituted for gelatin but has stronger setting properties (about 5 times greater) so less of it is required. Unlike gelatin, agar will set at room temperature.</Desc>
<Name>agar-agar</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>agave</Name>
<Desc>Also called century plant, this family of succulents grows in the southwestern United States, Mexico and Central America. Though poisonous when raw, agave has a sweet, mild flavor when baked or made into a syrup. Certain varieties are used in making the alcoholic beverages mescal, pulque and tequila.</Desc>
<Name>age</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>aged</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>aged meat</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>agedashi</Name>
<Desc>A Japanese dish of deep-fried tofu served with daikon, katsuobushi (dried bonito tuna flakes), ginger and a dipping sauce made of soy sauce and mirin.</Desc>
<Name>agemono</Name>
<Desc>A Japanese term referring to deep-frying (see deep-fry) and the foods produced from this cooking method. Tempura is the most famous of the Japanese foods cooked in this manner. Deep-frying is done in a pan called an <b>agemono-nabe</b>, which is similar to a Chinese wok.</Desc>
<Name>aging</Name>
<Desc></Desc>
<Name>aglio</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "garlic."</Desc>
<Name>aglio e olio</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "garlic and oil," referring to a dressing of garlic and hot olive oil used on pasta.</Desc>
<Name>agneau</Name>
<Desc>French for "lamb."</Desc>
<Name>agnello</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "lamb."</Desc>
<Name>agnolotti</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "priests' caps." Small crescent-shaped stuffed ravioli-style pasta.</Desc>
<Name>agresto</Name>
<Desc>Italian for "verjuice."</Desc>
<Name>agrodolce</Name>
<Desc>The Italian term for a sweet-and-sour flavor (dolce means sweet, agro is sour); synonymous with the French <em>aigre-doux</em>.</Desc>
<Name>agua</Name>
<Desc>Spanish and Portuguese, respectively, for "water."</Desc>
